<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thomas Lam</title>
    <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thomas Lam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016-19 &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Hugo Theme Basic&lt;/a&gt;. Made by &lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/siegerts&#39;&gt;@siegerts&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thomaslam.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Digest 3</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-3/</guid>
      <description>Weeks 07/07 - 07/13
Missed a few weeks oops 😬
News  Melinda Gates&amp;rsquo; new book on women empowerment as means to lift up society
 Added to reading list  Waymo completes 10 billion virtual miles in simulation [link]
 Why important: more training data =&amp;gt; better tech   Big ideas  Don&amp;rsquo;t try to be an influencer. Try to be a nerd instead
 Being a nerd pays off Being an influencer is a bad metric for self-worth; some people will never capture another people&amp;rsquo;s needs or attention; being a nerd is always a winning strategy  Difference between workaholics and high performers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Learning Road Map</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/ml-learning-road-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 15:05:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/ml-learning-road-map/</guid>
      <description>This is my planned learning roadmap of online courses covering topics I&amp;rsquo;m interested in exploring related to ML.
My goal is to complete most of these by my 25th birthday on July 4, 2020.
Update 7-10-19:  Added more courses that are just released by Udacity and Coursera (Data Engineer Nanodegree and Tensorflow Specialization)
 Coursera&amp;rsquo;s Machine Learning (Andrew Ng) Coursera&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning Specialication (Andrew Ng):  Neural Networks and Deep Learning Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization (IN PROGRESS) Structuring Machine Learning Projects Convolutional Neural Networks Sequence Models (IN PROGRESS)  Coursera&amp;rsquo;s Tensorflow in Practice Specialization fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Digest 2</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-2/</guid>
      <description>Week 04/22 - 04/28
News  He Jiankui - Chinese biophysics researcher claimed to create first gene editted human twin babies  CRISPR/Cas9 - technology used to create these babies (more layperson friendly video in this article) He uploaded promo videos on his Youtube channel Consequences (to He):  He&amp;rsquo;s announcement was met with widespread condemnation Chinese authorities suspended all his research activities and he was fired from his university Listed on Time&amp;rsquo;s 100 Most Influential People in 2019; CRISP co-inventor wrote the profile: &amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;He&amp;rsquo;s decision will likely be remembered as one of the most shocking misapplications of any scientific tool in our history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deriving cross-entropy loss gradient</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/deriving-cross-entropy-loss-gradient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/deriving-cross-entropy-loss-gradient/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post assumes familiarity of vector notations and strong knowledge of (partial) derivatives which is covered in a Multivariable Calculus class.
In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to show how to derive the gradient (vector of partial derivatives) of the cost function for logistic regression (also known as cross entropy loss). This is an important part of backpropagation step/gradient descent algorithm in training logistic regression model (which I have explained in an earlier blog post) as in order to update the model parameters, we need to know the gradient of the cost function with respect to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logistic regression explained</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/logistic-regression-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/logistic-regression-explained/</guid>
      <description>Logistic regression is one of the most famous ML models used in supervised learning settings. Despite the term &amp;ldquo;regression&amp;rdquo; in its name, this model is mostly used for classification tasks. An important distinction between logistic regression and another very popular supervised learning model, linear regression, is that the response variable is categorical for the former but continuous for the latter.
Most ML researchers use this model as a baseline in many supervised learning tasks because of its simplicity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning: an overview</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/machine-learning-an-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/machine-learning-an-overview/</guid>
      <description>In this introductory post, I introduce what Machine Learning is in hopefully a widely accessible language. I aim to minimize as many buzzwords as possible though certain terminologies such as matrices, vectors, statistical models, parameters, etc. will come up. A basic understanding of what these terms mean is assumed.
What is Machine Learning? According to computer scientist Arthur Samuel in 1959, Machine Learning is a subfield of Computer Science that gives “computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Digest 1</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-1/</guid>
      <description>Week 04/15 - 04/21
This is the first post of my weekly blog series on interesting things I&amp;rsquo;ve read/listened. I also try to keep myself accountable in terms of self education by including the What I am working on section at the end.
News  Notre Dame fire
 Sri Lanka Easter bombings
 Mueller report
 TLDR: found no conclusive evidence of Trump admin&amp;rsquo;s collusion with Russia; showed instances of Trump clearly frustrated about the investigation and tried to manipulate the justice system in many ways  Verge&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Andrew Yang</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 17:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Keeping a consistent blogging schedule has always been a challenge for me. Hopefully this time, I manage to get a few blog posts in before eventually life (and my procrastination tendency) kicks in. The purpose of this blog is to consolidate my thoughts on what I have learned on my journey in becoming a better software engineer/Machine Learning practitioner.
So yes most of my content is technical in nature. However, I do plan to write blog posts that are more mundane (book reviews, weekly digests of interesting reads and general reflections on life lessons).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 19:13:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Thomas Lam. I&amp;rsquo;m a (prospective) data engineer working at Capital One based in McClean, VA.
I&amp;rsquo;m interested in all things data science or machine learning related (and developing software in general). This website is meant to capture my journey on being a bit more knowledgeable about this vast and fascinating field.
Occasionally here you&amp;rsquo;ll find my collections/ramblings on books/articles/media I&amp;rsquo;ve consumed and other general non-technical stuff.
Feel free to reach out at tuananhlam95@gmail.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>