<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thomas Lam</title>
    <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thomas Lam</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2016-19 &lt;a href=&#39;https://github.com/siegerts/hugo-theme-basic&#39;&gt;Hugo Theme Basic&lt;/a&gt;. Made by &lt;a href=&#39;https://twitter.com/siegerts&#39;&gt;@siegerts&lt;/a&gt;.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thomaslam.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to ML and Data Science</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/intro-to-ml-and-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/intro-to-ml-and-data-science/</guid>
      <description>In this introductory post, I introduce what Machine Learning is in hopefully a widely accessible language. I aim to minimize as many buzzwords as possible though certain terminologies such as matrices, vectors, statistical models, parameters, etc. will come up. A basic understanding of what these terms mean is assumed.
What is Machine Learning? According to computer scientist Arthur Samuel in 1959, Machine Learning is a subfield of Computer Science that gives “computers the ability to learn without being explicitly programmed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Digest 1</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/weekly-digest-1/</guid>
      <description>Week 04/15 - 04/21
This is the first post of my weekly blog series on interesting things I&amp;rsquo;ve read/listened. I also try to keep myself accountable in terms of self education by including the What I am working on section at the end.
News  Notre Dame fire
 Sri Lanka Easter bombings
 Mueller report
 TLDR: found no conclusive evidence of Trump admin&amp;rsquo;s collusion with Russia; showed instances of Trump clearly frustrated about the investigation and tried to manipulate the justice system in many ways  Verge&amp;rsquo;s coverage of Andrew Yang</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 17:25:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thomaslam.github.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>Keeping a consistent blogging schedule has always been a challenge for me. Hopefully this time, I manage to get a few blog posts in before eventually life (and my procrastination tendency) kicks in. The purpose of this blog is to consolidate my thoughts on what I have learned on my journey in becoming a better software engineer/Machine Learning practitioner.
So yes most of my content is technical in nature. However, I do plan to write blog posts that are more mundane (book reviews, weekly digests of interesting reads and general reflections on life lessons).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>